ALAA ABDELBAKI

Mobile developer

+216 41 675 757

alaa.abdelbaki@outlook.com

Ariana, Tunisia

github.com/AlaaAbdelbaki

in /in/AlaaAbdelbaki

SUMMARY

I'm a mobile software engineer, with 2 years of experience in developing cross platform applications with the Flutter framework.

While developing mobile applications, I had the chance to also work on their backend, and ensure submitting them on the Google Play Store and the Apple App Store. **SKILLS**

Languages: Dart, Java, Kotlin, Swift, Javascript, C#.

Technologies: Flutter, Git, Android, iOS, Jenkins, NestJS,

ExrpessJS, NextJS.

EXPERIENCE -

07/2023 - Present

Flutter developer

EButler

- · Added new features to an existing Flutter application.
- · Worked on improving the real-time chatting feature using GetStream's Stream Chat library.
- · Maintained legacy code.
- · Upgraded the project to newer SDK versions, while performing the required code changes.
- · Pushed updates through the Google Play Store.
- Developed a redesigned version for mobile and web platforms while referencing a Figma design.
- Implemented new features and perform updates on a NestJS backend.
 Flutter / NestJs / Firebase / Firebase Cloud Messaging / GetStream / Google
 Play / App Store / WhatsApp Business API /

01/2022 - 06/2023

Software Engineer

Swiss Premium Negoce

- · Defined the project's usecases and requirements.
- · Decided which technologies to use based on the technical requirements.
- · Created the database design.
- · Developed the mobile application's UI based on an Adobe XD design.
- · Added new features and updating existing ones.
- · Developed backend features.
- Write backend documentatio
- Implemented Google Cloud APIs in the mobile application (Google Maps / Google Directions)
- · Integrated Stripe as a payment Gateway.
- Submitted and releacing the application on the Google Play Store and the Apple App Store.
 Flutter / Firebase / Firebase Cloud Messaging / Google Maps API / Google
 Directions API / ExpressJS / Stripe /

EDUCATION

09/2018 - 06/2022

Engineering degree in computer science

School

Followed the computer science program, and specialized in mobile applications development Worked on multiple projects in different fields during the cursus, including:

- · Mobile development.
- Web development.
- · Artificial intelligence.
- · computer vision.
- DevOps.

PROJECTS -

Flutter / ExpressJS

Elisys

A warehouse management mobile application, that helps technicians manage their products by simply scanning a QR code.

Flutter

Doroos

An online learning application, where users can choose from a wide variety of subjects and teachers, and chat with them in real time.

LANGUAGES

- · English Fluent
- · French B2
- · Arabic Native